<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Analysis</title>
    <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 01:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://geografia-au.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Jobs in Melbourne&#39;s SE</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/knowledge-jobs-in-melbourne-s-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 01:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/knowledge-jobs-in-melbourne-s-se/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with regular collaborator, Tim Nott, we investigated how to leverage from existing knowledge-based industries and supply chain components in eastern metropolitan Melbourne. The work formed part of a wider strategy designed to increase jobs in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maddington Kenwick Education and Training Services Profile</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/maddington-kenwick-education-and-training-services-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 07:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/maddington-kenwick-education-and-training-services-profile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study made recommendations for improvements to the focus and delivery of education related support programs for the region. The gap analysis was enhanced with a 10-year industry level labour market demand scenario model. GIS was used to map accessibility to education facilities for a community that was significantly transport disadvantaged.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Impact of Arts Venues in Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/economic-impact-of-arts-venues-in-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 06:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/economic-impact-of-arts-venues-in-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project measured the economic value of artists living and working in the City of Melbourne, focusing on the effect of arts spaces. We found we could use GIS and the City&amp;rsquo;s extensive database to measure the &amp;lsquo;gentrification effect&amp;rsquo;; the flow-on benefits of arts spaces on neighbourhoods over time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandurah Public Open Space Study</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/mandurah-public-open-space-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 06:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/mandurah-public-open-space-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Helping the City to take a more evidence-based approach to compiling a strategic plan for the City to affordably development and maintain public open space.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning for Sustainable Tourism on Tasmania&#39;s East Coast</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/planning-for-sustainable-tourism-on-tasmania-s-east-coast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 03:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/planning-for-sustainable-tourism-on-tasmania-s-east-coast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In partnership with Tim Nott and Hansen, along with cultural heritage and biodiversity specialists, we reviewed options for tourism development along the east coast of Tasmania; examining the challenges faced; opportunities; and investment needs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexandra Master Plan</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/alexandra-master-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/alexandra-master-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working with urban designers SJB&amp;nbsp;to activate the old rail precinct in Alexandra through a masterplan. The plan mixes tourism with community use, open space and commercial areas.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are your maps meaningless to 8% of your audience?</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/blog/2016/04/16/making_maps_accessible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 04:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/blog/2016/04/16/making_maps_accessible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;Humans are innately visual creatures. If you want confirmation of this in our industry, see what happens next time you’re in a long, exhausting meeting. As soon as someone pulls out a map or an image of some sort, people perk up. Conversations become more animated and decisions are made.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We love photos, images, maps and, at a pinch, charts. Its why graphics are significantly more effective (and increasingly popular) at communicating information than large tables of data.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Another fact about our biology, though, is that not all of us can see colour. While it seems disadvantageous to navigating in a world bursting with bright hues, about 8% of the population (mostly males) have some kind of colourblindness.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This has implications for mapping. When we learn how to map, we are taught basic techniques about colour, composition and detail. We need to remind ourselves regularly how we can make minor changes that will improve the meaning for everyone.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Some great resources about how to make your maps and charts ‘colour blind friendly’ can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://colorbrewer2.org/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Color Brewer&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dtpli.vic.gov.au/__data/assets/pdf_file/0006/227445/Communicating-Data-With-Colour.pdf&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Victorian State Government&lt;/a&gt;. QGIS, the free open source GIS, also has colourblind simulators.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Take a look at the following maps. They plot the probable&amp;nbsp;impact of job automation across Greater Sydney (in all cases, red indicates a higher probability).&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The first map&amp;nbsp;shows a common method for displaying variables: a red to green palette. The reds and greens in the map are essentially indistinguishable from each other for most colourblind people, rendering the map illegible. The other two maps show a more appropriate palette choice – red to blue, or shades of a single colour.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It’s not that hard to improve accessibility in maps. And as we map more and more of our world and our lives, it’s crucial to be inclusive of all vision types. Feel free to contact us at &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Geografia&lt;/a&gt; if you want to know more about this.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;Figure 1 Not So Accessible&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34; src=&#34;https://geografia-au.github.io/img/blog/large_Accessible_maps_Figure_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thumb accessible maps figure 1&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Figure 2 Accessible&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34; src=&#34;https://geografia-au.github.io/img/blog/medium_Accessible_maps_Figure_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thumb accessible maps figure 2&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34; src=&#34;https://geografia-au.github.io/img/blog/medium_Accessible_maps_Figure_3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thumb accessible maps figure 3&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Xavier</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/blog/2016/03/18/welcome_xavier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 01:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/blog/2016/03/18/welcome_xavier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fresh from AURIN, Xavier Goldie is working with Geografia now. An expert in GIS and spatial statistics, Xavier adds to our capabilities in spatial analysis. And we&amp;rsquo;ll add to his capabilities in economic and demographic&amp;nbsp;analysis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb xavier goldie low res&#34; src=&#34;https://geografia-au.github.io/img/blog/Xavier_Goldie_low_res.png&#34; class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology and Innovation Study</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/technology-and-innovation-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 01:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/technology-and-innovation-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An investigation of the the status of, and prospects for, the high tech sector in northern Malaysia. The study focused on whether targeted public funding would stimulate sustained private sector investment and, in doing so, contribute to the national economic development agenda. It included a survey of tech sector enterprises in the region.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greater Bunbury Global and Regional Futures</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/greater-bunbury-global-and-regional-futures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/greater-bunbury-global-and-regional-futures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An assessment of global, national and regional economic and demographic&amp;nbsp;trends and how they are affecting economic development prospects in Greater Bunbury. The work is part of the State&amp;rsquo;s Regional Centres Development Plan project for eight regional cities. Three key industries are likely to bring in new residents and investment over the next few decades: agribusiness, specialised manufacturing; and tourism.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Impact of Upgrades to Naracoorte Livestock Exchange</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/value-adding-to-the-naracoorte-livestock-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/value-adding-to-the-naracoorte-livestock-exchange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An economic impact assessment of investing in an upgrade to the livestock exchange shows a net benefit to the region.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School Site Optimisation in Greater Brisbane</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/school-site-optimisation-in-greater-brisbane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 23:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/school-site-optimisation-in-greater-brisbane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from the work in Moreton Bay, we further developed the school demand forecasting technique to determine whether a proposed new school site would minimise school catchment area overlaps in a region with a rapidly growing population.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation and atomisation and their spatial implications</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/blog/2015/10/04/automation_and_atomisation_and_their_spatial_implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 22:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/blog/2015/10/04/automation_and_atomisation_and_their_spatial_implications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If we accept that our economy is complex and never in equilibrium, then we need to keep an eye out for both small and large changes in it. You can never tell which one&amp;nbsp;might become a defining influence on what our job landscape and our cities look like. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In the case of &lt;b&gt;automation, &lt;/b&gt;a lot has been written on it already. We&amp;rsquo;ve been going through waves of job automation for at least a few centuries now, although the one we&amp;rsquo;re at the beginning of just might be one of the fastest we&amp;rsquo;ve ever experienced. Here in Australia a greater proportion of the population work; so more people want jobs, but automation could be removing them at a faster rate than they are replaced. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There are spatial implications to this. Here is a map of Greater Sydney. It shows place of residence data for all workers. The areas in&amp;nbsp;red are where,&amp;nbsp;according to current research, there is a higher probability of jobs being automated over the next few decades (go to &lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;https://geografia-au.github.io/atlas&#34;&gt;www.geografia.com.au/atlas&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to see a similar map for Greater Melbourne). &amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb automation small&#34; src=&#34;https://geografia-au.github.io/img/blog/large_Automation_small.png&#34; class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Obviously the outer suburbs already face significant challenges in accessing jobs and services. The pace at which job destruction runs relative to job creation in the outer suburbs&amp;nbsp;is another important issue to address.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;One of the ways in which it is already being addressed is through &lt;b&gt;job atomisation&lt;/b&gt;, or the shift to what is&amp;nbsp;known as the&amp;nbsp;on-demand economy. Task-oriented, part-time and casual work are all increasing as a share of total employment. We&amp;rsquo;ve recently interviewed some Melbourne-based on-demand workers. They are all educated, ambitious and, by all accounts, doing well.&amp;nbsp;Some of us might be forced down this pathway,&amp;nbsp;but the people we spoke to&amp;nbsp;all made a choice to pursue this less&amp;nbsp;certain&amp;nbsp;career trajectory. They say it&amp;nbsp;allows them to integrate work into their private lives and&amp;nbsp;get paid for work across&amp;nbsp;a variety of fields. They embrace co-working spaces more than business incubators, want more public transport and better access to High Speed Broadband.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It appears that&amp;nbsp;the creative classes we&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about for over a decade now, might finally be evolving into&amp;nbsp;this form. The trick for us as economic and urban&amp;nbsp;planners is to work out how to incorporate on-demand workers into our modelling and analysis. For example:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How&amp;nbsp;are we going to map commute patterns for someone who has three jobs? Where is their place of work?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In which municipality do we record their contribution to Gross Regional Product?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Will the on-demand economy counterbalance the agglomeration of jobs into the CBD? If the worker is more mobile, do they need to commute into the City everyday? For that matter, robots probably don&amp;rsquo;t need to either.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;A lot of the generic economic and population modelling tools we have are very unlikely to be up to the job of quantifying this more atomised economic landscape.&amp;nbsp;Its an interesting area to investigate and we&amp;rsquo;re working on it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can we learn from global cities?</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/blog/2015/06/15/what_can_we_learn_from_global_cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 05:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/blog/2015/06/15/what_can_we_learn_from_global_cities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Matt and Kevin&amp;nbsp;attended the 2015 New Cities Summit in Jakarta. This is a biennial conference run by the New Cities Foundation and its&amp;nbsp;all about lifting the game in city design, planning and management. They attended some interesting sessions and talked to people working around the world&amp;nbsp;on innovative, and often low cost, ways of making cities more efficient and liveable. Some of the things taken from the conference were:&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;As if&amp;nbsp;you didn&amp;rsquo;t know it by now, its pretty apparent that most of the world&amp;rsquo;s economic dynamism can be found in the rapidly growing cities of the world. Out of sheer necessity and made possible by the mass of human capital, there is burgeoning entrepreneurialism, with people leaping onto opportunities, using new and old tech to meet the needs of residents and businesses in innovative ways&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Australia is lagging the world in thinking about, and implementing all that is good about smart cities. That is, collecting and making available, data about how we use and move about our cities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Its accurate to say that some of the problems faced by rapidly growing megacities may have already been solved in Australia through larger scale market operations. For example, in Lagos, Nigeria (a city of around 13 million and growing by the same amount each year as the whole of Australia), a smart phone app is being used by a clever start up to effectively replicate the big supermarket supply chain logistics process; coordinating the distribution of fresh fruit and vegetables to small retailers throughout the city. The difference is, they do it for a fraction of the cost and there are thousands of individual retailers, not just a few&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The sheer scale of the challenges some developing world megacities face in water access, mobility, infrastructure shortfalls and housing is daunting. However, what we in Australia can take away from this is, that if cities with much larger challenges, and far fewer resources can make inroads into their problems, then our cities should have the resources to solve our own affordability, congestion and pollution issues&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Evidence-based planning and development faces all the same political hurdles in other cities as it does in Australia. We can devise&amp;nbsp;the best, data-driven solution we like,&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;but if we can&amp;rsquo;t win the political argument, it won&amp;rsquo;t necessarily be the solution that is chosen&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School Demand Forecasting in Moreton Bay</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/school-demand-forecasting-in-moreton-bay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 02:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/school-demand-forecasting-in-moreton-bay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A statistical and GIS-based analysis of school demand to identify the optimum site for a new school in Moreton Bay on behalf of Brisbane Catholic Education (BCE). It uses&amp;nbsp;real enrolment data, analysing trends over time to develop a probabilistic model of the growth rates for new catchment areas. This factors in travel patterns and &amp;lsquo;attractiveness&amp;rsquo; features to identify the better of two locations for a new school in the rapidly growing region. We then adapted and applied the model to assist BCE in determining the viability of a new primary/secondary school in a neighbouring region, factoring in the existing school provision, population growth and the likelihood that the new school would attract a sufficient number of new enrollees to warrant the investment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>