<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mapping on Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Planning</title>
    <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/categories/mapping/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mapping on Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Planning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 01:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://geografia-au.github.io/categories/mapping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>George Town Grants Program</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/george-town-grants-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 01:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/george-town-grants-program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Evaluation of the economic and social impact of a three year grants program designed to&amp;nbsp;stimulate private&amp;nbsp;investment and create jobs&amp;nbsp;in the World Heritage listed port city of George Town. We surveyed applicants and the wider business community to measure the success of the funding in meeting program objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Jobs in Melbourne&#39;s SE</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/knowledge-jobs-in-melbourne-s-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 01:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/knowledge-jobs-in-melbourne-s-se/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with regular collaborator, Tim Nott, we investigated how to leverage from existing knowledge-based industries and supply chain components in eastern metropolitan Melbourne. The work formed part of a wider strategy designed to increase jobs in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockingham Community Development Plan</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/rockingham-community-development-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 00:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/rockingham-community-development-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Comprehensive 10 year&amp;nbsp;community infrastructure plan. Our revenue estimation model ensured&amp;nbsp;affordable implementation&amp;nbsp;for the City. Follow up work included the preparation of a brief for an economic development plan and a community centre feasibility study.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boroondara Arts and Cultural Strategy</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/boroondara-arts-and-cultural-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 00:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/boroondara-arts-and-cultural-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introducing evidence-based analysis into arts participation and demand, we developed an arts and cultural strategy that emphasised the development of new and existing arts clusters to ensure the enthusiastic participants of Boroondara had access to a range of arts and cultural activities and facilities. This map below&amp;nbsp;was one of our earliest mapping efforts to identify spatial gaps in service delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alkimos Eglinton Population Projections and Facility and Services Needs Assessment</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/alkimos-eglinton-population-projections-and-facility-and-services-needs-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 07:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/alkimos-eglinton-population-projections-and-facility-and-services-needs-assessment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We ran population forecasts for the 2,100ha Alkimos Eglinton subdivision using a cellular automata method to populate the land through small contiguous cells. Then we used these figures to prepare a community infrastructure plan with staged rollout of schools and other community facilities over the development cycle of the new suburb.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binningup Demographic Profile and Infrastructure Need Assessment</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/binningup-demographic-profile-and-infrastructure-need-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 07:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/binningup-demographic-profile-and-infrastructure-need-assessment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By analysing the geography, history, demography and governance of 60 coastal towns around Australia, we found strong evidence for consistent trends that helped us to model the likely demographic change and infrastructure need for fast growing Binningup, south of Perth.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maddington Kenwick Education and Training Services Profile</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/maddington-kenwick-education-and-training-services-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 07:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/maddington-kenwick-education-and-training-services-profile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study made recommendations for improvements to the focus and delivery of education related support programs for the region. The gap analysis was enhanced with a 10-year industry level labour market demand scenario model. GIS was used to map accessibility to education facilities for a community that was significantly transport disadvantaged.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value of Manufacturing in South East Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/value-of-manufacturing-in-south-east-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 07:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/value-of-manufacturing-in-south-east-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Accurately documenting the size and value of&amp;nbsp;manufacturing in a particular region is both difficult and useful. In south east Melbourne we found its 71,300 workers generated almost $7.9 billion in GRP. This is 24% of the State&amp;rsquo;s manufacturing value and almost 7% of national manufacturing GDP. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Impact of Arts Venues in Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/economic-impact-of-arts-venues-in-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 06:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/economic-impact-of-arts-venues-in-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project measured the economic value of artists living and working in the City of Melbourne, focusing on the effect of arts spaces. We found we could use GIS and the City&amp;rsquo;s extensive database to measure the &amp;lsquo;gentrification effect&amp;rsquo;; the flow-on benefits of arts spaces on neighbourhoods over time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandurah Public Open Space Study</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/mandurah-public-open-space-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 06:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/mandurah-public-open-space-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Helping the City to take a more evidence-based approach to compiling a strategic plan for the City to affordably development and maintain public open space.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Opportunities from High Water Security in Wodonga</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/high-water-security-in-wodonga/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/high-water-security-in-wodonga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An analysis of the City&amp;rsquo;s comparative advantages in water-intensive manufacturing. The project highlighted good prospects for food and beverage manufacturing, which benefits from a number of other local advantages including&amp;nbsp;low water and other input&amp;nbsp;costs; access to a&amp;nbsp;skilled workforce; and a good logistics network.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning for Sustainable Tourism on Tasmania&#39;s East Coast</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/planning-for-sustainable-tourism-on-tasmania-s-east-coast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 03:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/planning-for-sustainable-tourism-on-tasmania-s-east-coast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In partnership with Tim Nott and Hansen, along with cultural heritage and biodiversity specialists, we reviewed options for tourism development along the east coast of Tasmania; examining the challenges faced; opportunities; and investment needs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Opportunities in an Ageing Population</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/business-opportunities-in-an-ageing-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 03:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/business-opportunities-in-an-ageing-population/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A study into the demographic change in East Gippsland and the business opportunities arising from a rapidly ageing population.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexandra Master Plan</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/alexandra-master-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/alexandra-master-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working with urban designers SJB&amp;nbsp;to activate the old rail precinct in Alexandra through a masterplan that mixes tourism with community use, open space and commercial areas.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mornington HBB Survey</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/mornington-hbb-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/projects/mornington-hbb-survey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Telephone and online survey to quantify and evaluate the scale and scope of home based businesses in the Mornington Peninsula&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>