<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mapping on Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Planning</title>
    <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/categories/mapping/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mapping on Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Planning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 04:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://geografia-au.github.io/categories/mapping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Are your maps meaningless to 8% of your audience?</title>
      <link>https://geografia-au.github.io/blog/2016/04/16/making_maps_accessible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 04:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia-au.github.io/blog/2016/04/16/making_maps_accessible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;Humans are innately visual creatures. If you want confirmation of this in our industry, see what happens next time you’re in a long, exhausting meeting. As soon as someone pulls out a map or an image of some sort, people perk up. Conversations become more animated and decisions are made.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We love photos, images, maps and, at a pinch, charts. Its why graphics are significantly more effective (and increasingly popular) at communicating information than large tables of data.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Another fact about our biology, though, is that not all of us can see colour. While it seems disadvantageous to navigating in a world bursting with bright hues, about 8% of the population (mostly males) have some kind of colourblindness.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This has implications for mapping. When we learn how to map, we are taught basic techniques about colour, composition and detail. We need to remind ourselves regularly how we can make minor changes that will improve the meaning for everyone.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Some great resources about how to make your maps and charts ‘colour blind friendly’ can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://colorbrewer2.org/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Color Brewer&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dtpli.vic.gov.au/__data/assets/pdf_file/0006/227445/Communicating-Data-With-Colour.pdf&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Victorian State Government&lt;/a&gt;. QGIS, the free open source GIS, also has colourblind simulators.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Take a look at the following maps. They plot the probable&amp;nbsp;impact of job automation across Greater Sydney (in all cases, red indicates a higher probability).&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The first map&amp;nbsp;shows a common method for displaying variables: a red to green palette. The reds and greens in the map are essentially indistinguishable from each other for most colourblind people, rendering the map illegible. The other two maps show a more appropriate palette choice – red to blue, or shades of a single colour.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It’s not that hard to improve accessibility in maps. And as we map more and more of our world and our lives, it’s crucial to be inclusive of all vision types. Feel free to contact us at &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Geografia&lt;/a&gt; if you want to know more about this.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;Figure 1 Not So Accessible&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34; src=&#34;https://geografia-au.github.io/img/blog/large_Accessible_maps_Figure_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thumb accessible maps figure 1&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Figure 2 Accessible&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34; src=&#34;https://geografia-au.github.io/img/blog/medium_Accessible_maps_Figure_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thumb accessible maps figure 2&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34; src=&#34;https://geografia-au.github.io/img/blog/medium_Accessible_maps_Figure_3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thumb accessible maps figure 3&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>