<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Analytics</title>
    <link>https://geografia.com.au/categories/economics/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2015 - 2016, Geografia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://geografia.com.au/categories/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Jobs in Melbourne&#39;s SE</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/knowledge-jobs-in-melbourne-s-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 01:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/knowledge-jobs-in-melbourne-s-se/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with regular collaborator, Tim Nott, we investigated how to leverage from existing knowledge-based industries and supply chain components in eastern metropolitan Melbourne. The work formed part of a wider strategy designed to increase jobs in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maddington Kenwick Education and Training Services Profile</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/maddington-kenwick-education-and-training-services-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 07:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/maddington-kenwick-education-and-training-services-profile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study made recommendations for improvements to the focus and delivery of education related support programs for the region. The gap analysis was enhanced with a 10-year industry level labour market demand scenario model. GIS was used to map accessibility to education facilities for a community that was significantly transport disadvantaged.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Impact of Arts Venues in Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/economic-impact-of-arts-venues-in-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 06:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/economic-impact-of-arts-venues-in-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project measured the economic value of artists living and working in the City of Melbourne, focusing on the effect of arts spaces. We found we could use GIS and the City&amp;rsquo;s extensive database to measure the &amp;lsquo;gentrification effect&amp;rsquo;; the flow-on benefits of arts spaces on neighbourhoods over time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning for Sustainable Tourism on Tasmania&#39;s East Coast</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/planning-for-sustainable-tourism-on-tasmania-s-east-coast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 03:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/planning-for-sustainable-tourism-on-tasmania-s-east-coast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In partnership with Tim Nott and Hansen, along with cultural heritage and biodiversity specialists, we reviewed options for tourism development along the east coast of Tasmania; examining the challenges faced; opportunities; and investment needs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology and Innovation Study</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/technology-and-innovation-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 01:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/technology-and-innovation-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An investigation of the the status of, and prospects for, the high tech sector in northern Malaysia. The study focused on whether targeted public funding would stimulate sustained private sector investment and, in doing so, contribute to the national economic development agenda. It included a survey of tech sector enterprises in the region.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greater Bunbury Global and Regional Futures</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/greater-bunbury-global-and-regional-futures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/greater-bunbury-global-and-regional-futures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An assessment of global, national and regional economic and demographic&amp;nbsp;trends and how they are affecting economic development prospects in Greater Bunbury. The work is part of the State&amp;rsquo;s Regional Centres Development Plan project for eight regional cities. Three key industries are likely to bring in new residents and investment over the next few decades: agribusiness, specialised manufacturing; and tourism.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Impact of Upgrades to Naracoorte Livestock Exchange</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/value-adding-to-the-naracoorte-livestock-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/value-adding-to-the-naracoorte-livestock-exchange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An economic impact assessment of investing in an upgrade to the livestock exchange shows a net benefit to the region.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School Site Optimisation in Greater Brisbane</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/school-site-optimisation-in-greater-brisbane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 23:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/school-site-optimisation-in-greater-brisbane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from the work in Moreton Bay, we further developed the school demand forecasting technique to determine whether a proposed new school site would minimise school catchment area overlaps in a region with a rapidly growing population.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School Demand Forecasting in Moreton Bay</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/school-demand-forecasting-in-moreton-bay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 02:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/school-demand-forecasting-in-moreton-bay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A statistical and GIS-based analysis of school demand to identify the optimum site for a new school in Moreton Bay on behalf of Brisbane Catholic Education (BCE). It uses&amp;nbsp;real enrolment data, analysing trends over time to develop a probabilistic model of the growth rates for new catchment areas. This factors in travel patterns and &amp;lsquo;attractiveness&amp;rsquo; features to identify the better of two locations for a new school in the rapidly growing region. We then adapted and applied the model to assist BCE in determining the viability of a new primary/secondary school in a neighbouring region, factoring in the existing school provision, population growth and the likelihood that the new school would attract a sufficient number of new enrollees to warrant the investment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greater Geraldton Expenditure Leakage Analysis</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/greater-geraldton-expenditure-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/greater-geraldton-expenditure-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working with Landcorp, the MidWest Development Commission and the City of Greater Geraldton, we quantified business, government and consumer expenditure leakage from the region. For consumer leakage, we used real expenditure data sourced from Quantium. The outcome included the identification of supply chain opportunities for new business enterprises in the region.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Opportunities in an Ageing Population</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/business-opportunities-in-an-ageing-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 03:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/business-opportunities-in-an-ageing-population/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A study into the demographic change in East Gippsland and the business opportunities arising from a rapidly ageing population.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mornington HBB Survey</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/mornington-hbb-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/mornington-hbb-survey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Telephone and online survey to quantify and evaluate the scale and scope of home based businesses in the Mornington Peninsula&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darebin Arts ESIA</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/darebin-arts-esia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 23:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/darebin-arts-esia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An economic and social impact assessment of the arts and creative sector in Darebin.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murchison Plan</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/murchison-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 23:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/murchison-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A resource analysis and community statement leading to a regional development framework for the five councils that make up north and western Tasmania. The work included an extensive land suitability assessment and collaboration with environmental and transport&amp;nbsp;planners and community engagement specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>East Arnhem Land Economic Review</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/east-arnhem-land-economic-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 04:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/east-arnhem-land-economic-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a study mapping and analysing the scale and type of employment growth potential for Galiwink&amp;rsquo;u, East Arnhem Land. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Population estimates, infrastructure capacity and an assessment of industry growth trends (notably in tourism and agribusiness), and other factors (e.g. job automation and centralisation) have been used to prepare scenarios for economic growth and development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>