<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog-rsses on Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Analysis</title>
    <link>http://geografia.com.au/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog-rsses on Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2015 - 2016, Geografia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 04:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://geografia.com.au/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Are your maps meaningless to 8% of your audience?</title>
      <link>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2016/04/16/making_maps_accessible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 04:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2016/04/16/making_maps_accessible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;Humans are innately visual creatures. If you want confirmation of this in our industry, see what happens next time you’re in a long, exhausting meeting. As soon as someone pulls out a map or an image of some sort, people perk up. Conversations become more animated and decisions are made.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We love photos, images, maps and, at a pinch, charts. Its why graphics are significantly more effective (and increasingly popular) at communicating information than large tables of data.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Another fact about our biology, though, is that not all of us can see colour. While it seems disadvantageous to navigating in a world bursting with bright hues, about 8% of the population (mostly males) have some kind of colourblindness.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This has implications for mapping. When we learn how to map, we are taught basic techniques about colour, composition and detail. We need to remind ourselves regularly how we can make minor changes that will improve the meaning for everyone.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Some great resources about how to make your maps and charts ‘colour blind friendly’ can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://colorbrewer2.org/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Color Brewer&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dtpli.vic.gov.au/__data/assets/pdf_file/0006/227445/Communicating-Data-With-Colour.pdf&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Victorian State Government&lt;/a&gt;. QGIS, the free open source GIS, also has colourblind simulators.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Take a look at the following maps. They plot the probable&amp;nbsp;impact of job automation across Greater Sydney (in all cases, red indicates a higher probability).&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The first map&amp;nbsp;shows a common method for displaying variables: a red to green palette. The reds and greens in the map are essentially indistinguishable from each other for most colourblind people, rendering the map illegible. The other two maps show a more appropriate palette choice – red to blue, or shades of a single colour.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It’s not that hard to improve accessibility in maps. And as we map more and more of our world and our lives, it’s crucial to be inclusive of all vision types. Feel free to contact us at &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Geografia&lt;/a&gt; if you want to know more about this.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;Figure 1 Not So Accessible&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/large_Accessible_maps_Figure_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thumb accessible maps figure 1&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Figure 2 Accessible&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/medium_Accessible_maps_Figure_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thumb accessible maps figure 2&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/medium_Accessible_maps_Figure_3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thumb accessible maps figure 3&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Xavier</title>
      <link>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2016/03/18/welcome_xavier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 01:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2016/03/18/welcome_xavier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fresh from AURIN, Xavier Goldie is working with Geografia now. An expert in GIS and spatial statistics, Xavier adds to our capabilities in spatial analysis. And we&amp;rsquo;ll add to his capabilities in economic and demographic&amp;nbsp;analysis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb xavier goldie low res&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/Xavier_Goldie_low_res.png&#34; class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation and atomisation and their spatial implications</title>
      <link>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/10/04/automation_and_atomisation_and_their_spatial_implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 22:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/10/04/automation_and_atomisation_and_their_spatial_implications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If we accept that our economy is complex and never in equilibrium, then we need to keep an eye out for both small and large changes in it. You can never tell which one&amp;nbsp;might become a defining influence on what our job landscape and our cities look like. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In the case of &lt;b&gt;automation, &lt;/b&gt;a lot has been written on it already. We&amp;rsquo;ve been going through waves of job automation for at least a few centuries now, although the one we&amp;rsquo;re at the beginning of just might be one of the fastest we&amp;rsquo;ve ever experienced. Here in Australia a greater proportion of the population work; so more people want jobs, but automation could be removing them at a faster rate than they are replaced. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There are spatial implications to this. Here is a map of Greater Sydney. It shows place of residence data for all workers. The areas in&amp;nbsp;red are where,&amp;nbsp;according to current research, there is a higher probability of jobs being automated over the next few decades (go to &lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/atlas&#34;&gt;www.geografia.com.au/atlas&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to see a similar map for Greater Melbourne). &amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb automation small&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/large_Automation_small.png&#34; class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Obviously the outer suburbs already face significant challenges in accessing jobs and services. The pace at which job destruction runs relative to job creation in the outer suburbs&amp;nbsp;is another important issue to address.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;One of the ways in which it is already being addressed is through &lt;b&gt;job atomisation&lt;/b&gt;, or the shift to what is&amp;nbsp;known as the&amp;nbsp;on-demand economy. Task-oriented, part-time and casual work are all increasing as a share of total employment. We&amp;rsquo;ve recently interviewed some Melbourne-based on-demand workers. They are all educated, ambitious and, by all accounts, doing well.&amp;nbsp;Some of us might be forced down this pathway,&amp;nbsp;but the people we spoke to&amp;nbsp;all made a choice to pursue this less&amp;nbsp;certain&amp;nbsp;career trajectory. They say it&amp;nbsp;allows them to integrate work into their private lives and&amp;nbsp;get paid for work across&amp;nbsp;a variety of fields. They embrace co-working spaces more than business incubators, want more public transport and better access to High Speed Broadband.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It appears that&amp;nbsp;the creative classes we&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about for over a decade now, might finally be evolving into&amp;nbsp;this form. The trick for us as economic and urban&amp;nbsp;planners is to work out how to incorporate on-demand workers into our modelling and analysis. For example:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How&amp;nbsp;are we going to map commute patterns for someone who has three jobs? Where is their place of work?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In which municipality do we record their contribution to Gross Regional Product?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Will the on-demand economy counterbalance the agglomeration of jobs into the CBD? If the worker is more mobile, do they need to commute into the City everyday? For that matter, robots probably don&amp;rsquo;t need to either.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;A lot of the generic economic and population modelling tools we have are very unlikely to be up to the job of quantifying this more atomised economic landscape.&amp;nbsp;Its an interesting area to investigate and we&amp;rsquo;re working on it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can we learn from global cities?</title>
      <link>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/06/15/what_can_we_learn_from_global_cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 05:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/06/15/what_can_we_learn_from_global_cities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Matt and Kevin&amp;nbsp;attended the 2015 New Cities Summit in Jakarta. This is a biennial conference run by the New Cities Foundation and its&amp;nbsp;all about lifting the game in city design, planning and management. They attended some interesting sessions and talked to people working around the world&amp;nbsp;on innovative, and often low cost, ways of making cities more efficient and liveable. Some of the things taken from the conference were:&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;As if&amp;nbsp;you didn&amp;rsquo;t know it by now, its pretty apparent that most of the world&amp;rsquo;s economic dynamism can be found in the rapidly growing cities of the world. Out of sheer necessity and made possible by the mass of human capital, there is burgeoning entrepreneurialism, with people leaping onto opportunities, using new and old tech to meet the needs of residents and businesses in innovative ways&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Australia is lagging the world in thinking about, and implementing all that is good about smart cities. That is, collecting and making available, data about how we use and move about our cities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Its accurate to say that some of the problems faced by rapidly growing megacities may have already been solved in Australia through larger scale market operations. For example, in Lagos, Nigeria (a city of around 13 million and growing by the same amount each year as the whole of Australia), a smart phone app is being used by a clever start up to effectively replicate the big supermarket supply chain logistics process; coordinating the distribution of fresh fruit and vegetables to small retailers throughout the city. The difference is, they do it for a fraction of the cost and there are thousands of individual retailers, not just a few&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The sheer scale of the challenges some developing world megacities face in water access, mobility, infrastructure shortfalls and housing is daunting. However, what we in Australia can take away from this is, that if cities with much larger challenges, and far fewer resources can make inroads into their problems, then our cities should have the resources to solve our own affordability, congestion and pollution issues&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Evidence-based planning and development faces all the same political hurdles in other cities as it does in Australia. We can devise&amp;nbsp;the best, data-driven solution we like,&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;but if we can&amp;rsquo;t win the political argument, it won&amp;rsquo;t necessarily be the solution that is chosen&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>These locations should be the NBN rollout priority areas</title>
      <link>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/04/27/high_speed_broadband_can_accelerate_victoria_s_economic_growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 02:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/04/27/high_speed_broadband_can_accelerate_victoria_s_economic_growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;Our recent study for Southern Melbourne RDA looked into the economic benefits of the NBN and included a survey of over 300 businesses in the region.&amp;nbsp;These businesses were in precincts that were not included in the current NBN rollout plan.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The survey examined the quality of the current Internet access in the precincts; the effect this was having on business productivity and growth; and the expected benefits that high speed broadband (HSB – in this case, the NBN) would bring to their business.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Amongst many results, the study found that HSB was expected to deliver increased productivity, expansion into new manufacturing and even the reshoring of more traditional manufacturing. It also concluded that the scale of these benefits would vary depending on the type of business and its market focus.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The enterprises most likely to gain from HSB were:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; •  High value (measured by turnover); large employers;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; •    Export oriented businesses; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; •  Larger manufacturing, construction and wholesaling enterprises.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In the short term, these HSB-related gains are presumed to be driven by two major trends:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;1. The increasing integration of international markets and intensive use of information technologies. This is placing pressure on businesses to adopt new programs and communications tools and is particularly relevant to exporters.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;2.  The shift from traditional, production-based manufacturing towards a service-orientation. That is, advanced and high-value manufacturing are increasingly run as service consultancy-based enterprises, heavily reliant on complex information exchange.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Obviously, then, the NBN has a clear impact on Victoria’s economic growth trajectory. Moreover, if these survey results reflect businesses across the metropolitan area, then we can map ‘HSB-responsive’ industries and, in doing so, point to where the NBN can and should be prioritised to optimise the economic benefits (see maps below). Providing NBN in these locations has the potential to significantly accelerate Victoria’s economic growth, particularly in the highly important advanced manufacturing sector.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;As businesses are far more willing to be early adopters of HSB than households, prioritising these clusters over residential areas can fast track both NBN take-up and economic growth: a win-win for Victoria and NBN Co.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;Figure 1 &amp;nbsp; The Ideal NBN Priority Hotspots&lt;br&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb impact of nbn map 1&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/Impact_of_NBN_Map_1.jpg&#34; class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Figure 2 &amp;nbsp; The Ideal Advanced Manufacturing&amp;nbsp;NBN Priority Hotspots&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb impact of nbn map 2&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/Impact_of_NBN_Map_2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh open data: three new data sets to help understand our cities</title>
      <link>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/03/18/fresh_and_unwrapped_three_new_open_data_sets_to_help_understand_our_cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/03/18/fresh_and_unwrapped_three_new_open_data_sets_to_help_understand_our_cities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;As advocates of &lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_data&#34;&gt;open data&lt;/a&gt; initiatives, we&#39;re pleased to discover three freshly released data sets available to planners and economists seeking to understand Victoria&#39;s cities. Gaining access to these data sets is hugely important for planning and managing cities. Congratulations to the government departments responsible for compiling and releasing these important data sets - the open data movement is gaining momentum!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. Detailed commercial, industrial and residential floor space data&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://cdb.io/1AyR701 &#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb image2&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/medium_image2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://www.ga.gov.au&#34;&gt;Geoscience Australia&lt;/a&gt; has worked hard to collect and distribute&amp;nbsp;floor space data for industrial, commercial and residential uses at a small area (SA1) level across Australia. This is the first time (in our knowledge) that floor space data has been released at such a fine grain level. Until now, analysts have relied on very&amp;nbsp;coarse geographical data, such as ABS destination zones or SA2s. These coarse geographies don&#39;t capture the intricacies of localised&amp;nbsp;land use differences.&amp;nbsp;GA&#39;s data set can be used to&amp;nbsp;measure the spatial distribution of key land uses across the city, or&amp;nbsp;act as a proxy measure for building heights, employment, and job density.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Interactive map of industrial areas in Melbourne:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://cdb.io/1AyR701&#34;&gt;http://cdb.io/1AyR701&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Source data:&lt;b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://www.ga.gov.au/scientific-topics/hazards/risk-impact/nexis&#34;&gt;http://www.ga.gov.au/scientific-topics/hazards/risk-impact/nexis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. Property parcels - Victoria wide!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb image3&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/medium_image3.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;That&#39;s all that needs to be said -&amp;nbsp;there are&amp;nbsp;a million potential uses for this dataset.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Source data:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;https://www.data.vic.gov.au/data/dataset/parcel-view-vicmap-property&#34;&gt;https://www.data.vic.gov.au/data/dataset/parcel-view-vicmap-property&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. Pre-1994 Local Government Boundaries&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://cdb.io/1AySUSX &#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb image1&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/medium_image1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;These old boundaries&amp;nbsp;are fun for the nostalgically inclined. However, they are also really useful when analysing or visualising data from any Census prior to 1996.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Interactive map of Victoria&#39;s pre-Kennet LGA boundaries:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://cdb.io/1AySUSX&#34;&gt;http://cdb.io/1AySUSX&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Source data:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;https://www.data.vic.gov.au/data/dataset/local-government-areas-for-victoria-prior-to-the-1994-amalgamations&#34;&gt;https://www.data.vic.gov.au/data/dataset/local-government-areas-for-victoria-prior-to-the-1994-amalg...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some job clusters are easier to grow</title>
      <link>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/03/11/some_job_clusters_are_easier_to_grow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/03/11/some_job_clusters_are_easier_to_grow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;Normal job distribution around our capital cities shows extreme concentrations in the city centres, with an outward&amp;nbsp;spread of clusters usually located around major infrastructure (e.g. roads, hospitals, industrial areas). Encouraging the growth of jobs in some of the outlying clusters is an important strategic planning objective as it can improve job accessibility for outer suburban residents and spread the transport load around the city.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A considerable amount is known about&amp;nbsp;how these clusters emerge; whether there are underlying patterns to their formation; and how much&amp;nbsp;influence can be applied to these patterns. The research we did on the knowledge economy reminded us that Melbourne’s metropolitan job clusters appear to fit a predictable hierarchical pattern based on size. It’s a fairly familiar pattern, with one variation of it known colloquially as the 80:20 rule: where 80% of something is accounted for by 20% of the whole. While those ratios are not the specific pattern we found, it’s part of the same family.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Using Census data on job location we mapped where jobs were located and where the clusters appeared (see attached map - the red indicates job clusters using a 2km threshold).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb prelim   2000m clusters&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/large_Prelim_-_2000m_clusters.png&#34; class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;To tell whether the clusters fit our pattern, we plotted them on a chart. When transformed a certain way, they should follow a straight line, and they do (see attached chart). In fact a lot of economic phenomena conform to this pattern. So this in itself should not be surprising.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb test plot1&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/large_Test_Plot1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But what does it mean? It means that job clustering, or the concentration in numbers of jobs across a metropolitan area, is being influenced by a set of economic factors that, ultimately, create a relatively predictable pattern. If this pattern is resilient, then it tells us something about which clusters will be easier to grow. Anything above the line is going to be a challenge and anything below the line may be easier.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The plot below shows the retail sector for these same clusters. There are&amp;nbsp;outliers in this plot, which&amp;nbsp;suggests we may need to work a little more on defining the clusters. Nonetheless, there is still a very&amp;nbsp;obvious linear relationship here, which&amp;nbsp;demonstrates a strong size&amp;nbsp;hierarchy. This makes sense, given what we know about how the&amp;nbsp;retail sector is spatially distributed.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb retail cluster plot&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/large_Retail_Cluster_Plot.png&#34; class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;These complex relationships are likely to be caused by a combination of&amp;nbsp;different factors such as distance, land suitability, history and so forth. Irrespective of the cause,&amp;nbsp;the size of job clusters do appear to fit this well-established pattern. This clearly affords us&amp;nbsp;a clue about how to prioritise metropolitan growth strategies.&amp;nbsp;Additionally, with cheaper and more readily available data analysis, we can do this more efficiently and make a really cost effective and valuable contribution to policy making. Our next step is to start examining what might be the dominant drivers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A message for the Intergenerational Report: Overseas migration is a bit like the fountain of youth</title>
      <link>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/03/06/a_message_for_the_intergenerational_report_overseas_migration_is_enormous_and_keeping_us_young/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 04:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/03/06/a_message_for_the_intergenerational_report_overseas_migration_is_enormous_and_keeping_us_young/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It’s pleasing to see the Intergenerational Report focusing on long-term demographic trends and their implications for Australia. It reminds us that international migration has been, and is likely to continue to be, a major factor for change, influencing the pace and the makeup of growth in our communities.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;With Advanced Demographic Modelling, we’ve been examining what alternative long-term migration scenarios might mean for different municipalities. Obviously, the scale of net overseas migration has been the key reason some areas have grown rapidly, and it needs to be part of the strategic thinking by councils wishing to address population decline.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Overseas migration’s effect on age is even more interesting. Historical data shows it has significantly (and by that, we mean statistically significantly) reduced the median age of local government areas such as the City of Melbourne, Port Phillip, Greater Dandenong and Monash in Victoria and Brisbane, Gold Coast and McKinlay in Queensland (the map for Melbourne is shown below). In fact, if we exclude the new residents who arrived from overseas, the median ages would be up to 12 years higher in some of these places. That’s critical information for any local government service planner.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Overseas migration has had the most significant influence on the pace of growth and the age profile in these and other municipalities. Consequently, assumptions about future migration rates will have a major influence on infrastructure demand, labour force size, the dependency ratio and, ultimately, the Commonwealth budget. Whatever assumption you make about overseas migration should be central to&amp;nbsp;any intergenerational reporting.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb melbourne map&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/large_Melbourne_Map.png&#34; class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we really expect CBD densities in regional WA?</title>
      <link>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/02/17/can_we_really_expect_cbd_densities_in_regional_wa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 06:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/02/17/can_we_really_expect_cbd_densities_in_regional_wa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;The Greater Bunbury area (150km south of Perth) has a population of 75,000 and is forecast to grow to 100,000 by 2031 and 150,000 by 2050. A review of land supply by the State planning authority concluded that demand could be satisfied through a combination of an urban infill program and the release of over 2,000ha of land for Greenfield development. At first glance this seemed plausible. However, a closer examination revealed some fundamental flaws in the underlying assumptions that would have resulted in a land shortage of between 300 and 1,000ha.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The State Government’s population and housing capacity assumptions included the claims that every dwelling will be occupied by 2.5 people; that dwellings will always be 100% occupied; and that there will be no holiday homes or short term accommodation in the region. Most importantly, it also assumed housing densities could reach inner metropolitan levels within a few years, predicated on a population ageing rate that contradicts the population projections for the region, which emphasise the relatively young age of new residents. Together these assumptions allowed up to 75,000 new residents to be accommodated through some infill and the release of a little over 2,000ha of land.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We took a look at housing development trends around Australia, including population densities and how they have changed. From this we developed a model to predict the most likely population and housing density given the regional setting. This was based on an analysis of data over 12,000 small area sites around Australia. We found we could group regional areas into different density clusters and that Bunbury sat in ‘Group 4’, already one of the more densely developed regional cities. In order to accommodate new residents into the land set aside within the regional growth strategy, Bunbury would have to ‘step up’ to group 6; something that was unprecedented in the historical data (see chart). &amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb bunbury article 1&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/medium_Bunbury_article_1.jpg&#34; class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Dwelling and population density are the result of dynamic processes with multiple interactions and feedbacks between dwelling type, household structure, income, proximity to employment hubs, amenity, land prices and occupancy rates. The non-linear relationships between these factors make it critical that strategic planning draws on models that are sophisticated enough to measure them and provide plausible scenarios for growth. For example, the relationship between dwelling density and household size varies with densely developed areas attracting a mix of non-family households with small households and large group houses. Locations with good amenity also have a high proportion of holiday homes and/or temporary tourism accommodation, which reduces the proportion of permanent residents. Multilevel apartments also attract rental investors which means more transient populations and higher vacancy rates.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The bottom line was that the State Planning Authority’s land demand estimate was between 360ha and 1,000ha short of what will be required to accommodate the projected population.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The application of maximum dwelling yields multiplied by an average household size for all dwelling types and locations does not account for the dynamic way in which population, proximity, amenity and dwelling density interact. Oversimplified population calculations coupled with a mismatch between density targets and the reality of housing choices (as shown in the Census data) has the potential create housing shortages and increase housing prices. Application of a more sophisticated technique that draws on real world data can overcome these problems.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;wysiwyg-color-silver&#34;&gt;&#34;Bunbury 03&#34; by Bmorey at the English language Wikipedia. Licensed under CC BY-SA 3.0 via Wikimedia Commons - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Bunbury_03.jpg#mediaviewer/File:Bunbury_03.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;wysiwyg-color-silver&#34;&gt;http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Bunbury_03.jpg#mediaviewer/File:Bunbury_03.jpg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveability, Efficiency and the Knowledge Economy</title>
      <link>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/02/17/liveability_efficiency_and_the_knowledge_economy_92fbc55a_2d2c_4ced_b13d_490df0313618/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 00:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/02/17/liveability_efficiency_and_the_knowledge_economy_92fbc55a_2d2c_4ced_b13d_490df0313618/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;Liveability, spatial efficiency and the knowledge economy are important to Melbourne’s economic future and the way they are related to one another makes them relevant subject matter for strategic metropolitan planning. This is particularly so for transport infrastructure priorities and whether liveability near knowledge job clusters should be a metropolitan-wide concern. Updating some work done for Melbourne’s 2012 Knowledge Cities conference has revealed some ‘low hanging fruit’ in the spatial distribution of the knowledge sector that may help shed light on the options for a more liveable and efficient city.&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;What is the Knowledge Economy?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;There are many different ways to classify the knowledge economy, but the most meaningful considers both the industry sector and a worker’s occupation. That is, you can be in the knowledge sector, but not necessarily a knowledge worker. With this in mind, there are around 181,000 knowledge economy jobs in Greater Melbourne (about 11% of all jobs) and the entire knowledge economy is worth about $150b to the State’s economy (a little under half).&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;What Does the Knowledge Economy Look Like?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;For the purposes of this article, there are four clearly related dimensions to the knowledge economy that are especially relevant.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;1.  Knowledge economy workers are usually younger, more educated and use public transport&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Liveability and the knowledge economy go hand in hand: knowledge workers seek liveable environs in which to work and live. It should come as no surprise, then, that there are clear demographic differences between knowledge workers and the rest of the workforce. For example, they are:&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;• Usually younger (a high proportion of 25-44 year olds and fewer 45+);&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;•    Twice as likely to have a bachelor degree or higher;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;•  Almost twice as likely to be in a high income band;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;•   Almost five times as likely to travel by public transport; and&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;•  More likely to vote for left of centre parties .&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;2.   No matter where they work, knowledge workers prefer to live nearby&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Following on from the first point, the location of knowledge workers and jobs are positively correlated; more so than for the rest of the workforce. That is, regardless of where the knowledge economy job is (i.e. in a cluster or not), employment self-containment is higher for knowledge workers, but particularly so around the larger knowledge job clusters. Consequently, the residential distribution of knowledge workers is also somewhat clustered.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;3. Knowledge enterprises seek agglomeration benefits&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;All jobs in Greater Melbourne cluster in and around the CBD, as well as in major regional centres such as Dandenong, Laverton and Campbellfield . However, knowledge economy jobs are much more concentrated. There is a wealth of research on the importance of this agglomeration (or clustering) to the knowledge economy. We’ll come back to this point later.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;4.   The knowledge economies: plural not singular&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Finally, the knowledge economy is not a single entity. It is made up of subsectors with different patterns of distribution of jobs and workers. In this analysis, the subsectors are:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;1. Finance, Banking and Insurance (Finance).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;2.  Design related industries, such as architecture (Design).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;3.    Cultural Industries, such as performing arts (Cultural).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;4.   Telecommunications, IT and Media (IMT).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;5.    Health workers, such as specialist medical services, but not general practitioners or nurses (Health).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;6. R&amp;amp;D and Higher Education (R&amp;amp;D).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Figure 1 shows the breakdown of jobs and workers in these segments for Greater Melbourne.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The spatial concentrations (or clusters) of these jobs and where the workers live can be identified through some simple statistical analysis at the SA2 level. Figure 2 shows where the knowledge jobs are clustered in Melbourne and Figure 3, where knowledge workers live.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;So What Does this all Mean?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Table 1 summarises some of the main elements of the spatial distribution of knowledge jobs and workers (industry subsectors are in descending order of employment self-containment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;Overall, Finance, Design, Cultural and IMT workers are the most likely to live near their work. By contrast, with a few local exceptions, there is very little and even a negative correlation between where R&amp;amp;D and Health workers live and where they work (Table 2).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;As Figure 1 shows, there are clearly defined knowledge clusters around the CBD and near universities such as Monash in Clayton, Latrobe in Kingsbury, RMIT in nearby Bundoora and Victoria University in Footscray. In the CBD, knowledge workers are much more inclined to live nearby. However, this is less likely elsewhere and very unlikely for Health and R&amp;amp;D employees, who make up the bulk of the non-CBD based knowledge workers. &amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;What does this mean? We know that knowledge workers earn more than the general population and therefore have greater choice about where they live. It is logical to assume, then, they will choose to live in high amenity areas. The fact that they do not live near the outer metropolitan knowledge job clusters shows they value this over proximity to work.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;If, then, there is a desire to make Melbourne more efficient, there are two options that immediately come to mind.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;1. Brains on Trains : plan transport connections to improve the access between the residential and job clusters&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We can make it easier for knowledge workers to commute. Not least because of the better networks in the inner city, knowledge workers are more likely to use public transport and facilitating this travel between all of the job and residential clusters should be part of transport planning considerations, particularly major proposals such as the Melbourne Metro. This, and similar routes, are effectively information networks moving ‘brains on trains’ between key locations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;2. Attracting workers to job clusters&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;If knowledge workers are inclined to trade off proximity to work for higher amenity then what about removing that need by providing better amenity around the job clusters? This means investing in residential facilities and services in places such as Monash, Dandenong South, East Werribee and Bundoora. If we encourage higher residential density as part of this, then we will also increase catchment area sizes to justify the investment. It will also provide a better choice of housing for knowledge workers at different life cycle stages. Assuming R&amp;amp;D and Health workers ultimately have similar preferences to other knowledge workers, then the low hanging fruit for improving employment self-containment is to be found here.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But should we be thinking about influencing the housing decisions of knowledge workers, or the business location decisions of knowledge enterprises? Consider this: knowledge economy jobs concentrate significantly more than other jobs and more than the knowledge workers themselves. This is thought to be because industries gain significant agglomeration benefits and/or rely on very specific infrastructure assets (such as universities or hospitals). Any policy to encourage higher employment self-containment will need to consider whether it is easier to bring the jobs to the workers, or vice versa. Ultimately, it is probably more efficient to fund relatively easy-to-replicate (if not always cheap) residential amenity than the infrastructure needed to attract new enterprises.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;Figure 4 shows selected knowledge sector job and residential clusters, along with the current and proposed rail lines in Melbourne.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;These thoughts only scratch the surface of the knowledge economy and its relationship to infrastructure planning in Melbourne. There is substantial scope for further analysis, which will help understand who is making what sort of locational decision and why, and, ultimately, how to influence this. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing market mismatches in Northern Tasmania</title>
      <link>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/02/06/housing_market_mismatches_in_northern_tasmania/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/02/06/housing_market_mismatches_in_northern_tasmania/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;In northern Tasmania, the population is growing slowly, but ageing rapidly. While the housing supply pipeline appears to be more than adequate to meet the modest demand, the rapid ageing of the population means that the type of current and planned housing stock is increasingly unsuited to the population, who are living in smaller households, consequently, seeking smaller houses and lots. The counter-intuitive result is that, although, at best, the population may grow by 25% (from around 150,000 to 180,000).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The data is fairly extensive and reliable and all point to a complex pattern that forms an important strategic issue for regional housing. On one side of the ledger, the population is ageing, growth is slowing and rural-urban migration has almost run its course (there is a noticeable counter-urbanisation trend). On the other side, households are getting smaller; lot and dwelling sizes have stopped increasing; house prices have flatlined; and housing construction rates has been both steady and pretty consistently focused on detached dwellings in general residential zones.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Thumb tas housing article 1&#34; src=&#34;http://geografia.com.au/img/blog/large_Tas_Housing_article_1.jpg&#34; class=&#34;wysiwyg-float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Yet the ageing householder is increasingly interested in small lot, semi-detached living. To date, the way around this has been through a de facto densification trend of strata title housing development. The evidence here and elsewhere in regional Australia is that there is growing demand for smaller lots and more diversity in housing. Modelling suggests there will be demand for maybe 1-2,000 new detached houses over the next 20 years, but possibly 13-15,000 semi-detached dwellings, flats and apartments. Unlike in Greater Bunbury, in this case, the land supply is adequate, its just that the housing market and planning system is not encouraging the mix of housing that people are starting to preference. Does this mean that Northern Tasmania will end up with a lot of unwanted housing stock?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to revitalise an underperforming pedestrian mall</title>
      <link>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2014/02/17/how_to_revitalise_an_underperforming_pedestrian_mall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://geografia.com.au/blog/2014/02/17/how_to_revitalise_an_underperforming_pedestrian_mall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;There are many interacting factors that influence the choice an individual makes when deciding where to shop and recreate. Understanding this requires a suitably sophisticated approach based on good evidence. Extensive consultation, including consumer surveys, provided us with data we could use to quantify the relative importance of activation, amenity and retail choice when it comes to where they would shop in the Greater Shepparton area. From this we identified the most cost-effective way to increase visitor numbers to Shepparton’s Maude Street Mall. The analysis tested the effect of everything from extended opening hours, running more events, a broader retail mix, landscaping, parking and opening the mall to vehicle traffic.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Analysing the data involved the use of a method called structural equation modelling. This compared the separate and combined effect of different sets of improvements that regional residents had said were essential if they were to consider coming back to the Mall. By rolling all of these improvements out over a 10 year period, it was estimated that an additional 1.2 million visitors could be attracted to the Mall. Perhaps the most important finding was that individual improvements would have a minimal impact. As the table below shows, only combinations or bundles would have a statistically measurable effect on visitor numbers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;There had been a very vocal group in the community arguing for re-opening the Mall to vehicle traffic. However, contrary to expectations, residents said the lack of car access had little to do with them going elsewhere. Parking right outside the shop just wasn’t that important. Furthermore, given the cost (at least $4 million to re-open the Mall to traffic, plus an additional $5 million to replace the civic space that would be lost), modest improvements to amenity and more active streetscapes were far better value for money.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;These findings confirmed our 13 case studies of regional malls around Australia. This found that simple things like shade, seating, retail choice and activity were more closely associated with successful Mall’s than road access or parking.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Our analysis demonstrated that when it comes to mall revitalisation there is no silver bullet. The best approach is bundled improvements that improve amenity, create more choice for visitors and provide more accessible and affordable parking.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>