<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Analytics</title>
    <link>https://geografia.com.au/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2015 - 2017, Geografia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 04:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://geografia.com.au/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Are your maps meaningless to 8% of your audience?</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2016/04/16/making_maps_accessible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 04:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2016/04/16/making_maps_accessible/</guid>
      <description>Humans are innately visual creatures. If you want confirmation of this in our industry, see what happens next time you’re in a long, exhausting meeting. As soon as someone pulls out a map or an image of some sort, people perk up. Conversations become more animated and decisions are made.&amp;nbsp;
We love photos, images, maps and, at a pinch, charts. Its why graphics are significantly more effective (and increasingly popular) at communicating information than large tables of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Xavier</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2016/03/18/welcome_xavier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 01:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2016/03/18/welcome_xavier/</guid>
      <description>Fresh from AURIN, Xavier Goldie is working with Geografia now. An expert in GIS and spatial statistics, Xavier adds to our capabilities in spatial analytics. And we&amp;rsquo;ll add to his capabilities in economic and demographic&amp;nbsp;analysis.&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation and atomisation and their spatial implications</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/10/04/automation_and_atomisation_and_their_spatial_implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 22:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/10/04/automation_and_atomisation_and_their_spatial_implications/</guid>
      <description>If we accept that our economy is complex and never in equilibrium, then we need to keep an eye out for both small and large changes in it. You can never tell which one&amp;nbsp;might become a defining influence on what our job landscape and our cities look like. In the case of automation, a lot has been written on it already. We&amp;rsquo;ve been going through waves of job automation for at least a few centuries now, although the one we&amp;rsquo;re at the beginning of just might be one of the fastest we&amp;rsquo;ve ever experienced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can we learn from global cities?</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/06/15/what_can_we_learn_from_global_cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 05:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/06/15/what_can_we_learn_from_global_cities/</guid>
      <description>Matt and Kevin&amp;nbsp;attended the 2015 New Cities Summit in Jakarta. This is a biennial conference run by the New Cities Foundation and its&amp;nbsp;all about lifting the game in city design, planning and management. They attended some interesting sessions and talked to people working around the world&amp;nbsp;on innovative, and often low cost, ways of making cities more efficient and liveable. Some of the things taken from the conference were:&amp;nbsp;
As if&amp;nbsp;you didn&amp;rsquo;t know it by now, its pretty apparent that most of the world&amp;rsquo;s economic dynamism can be found in the rapidly growing cities of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>These locations should be the NBN rollout priority areas</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/04/27/high_speed_broadband_can_accelerate_victoria_s_economic_growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 02:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/04/27/high_speed_broadband_can_accelerate_victoria_s_economic_growth/</guid>
      <description>Our recent study for Southern Melbourne RDA looked into the economic benefits of the NBN and included a survey of over 300 businesses in the region.&amp;nbsp;These businesses were in precincts that were not included in the current NBN rollout plan.&amp;nbsp;
The survey examined the quality of the current Internet access in the precincts; the effect this was having on business productivity and growth; and the expected benefits that high speed broadband (HSB – in this case, the NBN) would bring to their business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh open data: three new data sets to help understand our cities</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/03/18/fresh_and_unwrapped_three_new_open_data_sets_to_help_understand_our_cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/03/18/fresh_and_unwrapped_three_new_open_data_sets_to_help_understand_our_cities/</guid>
      <description>As advocates of open data initiatives, we&#39;re pleased to discover three freshly released data sets available to planners and economists seeking to understand Victoria&#39;s cities. Gaining access to these data sets is hugely important for planning and managing cities. Congratulations to the government departments responsible for compiling and releasing these important data sets - the open data movement is gaining momentum!
1. Detailed commercial, industrial and residential floor space data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some job clusters are easier to grow</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/03/11/some_job_clusters_are_easier_to_grow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/03/11/some_job_clusters_are_easier_to_grow/</guid>
      <description>Normal job distribution around our capital cities shows extreme concentrations in the city centres, with an outward&amp;nbsp;spread of clusters usually located around major infrastructure (e.g. roads, hospitals, industrial areas). Encouraging the growth of jobs in some of the outlying clusters is an important strategic planning objective as it can improve job accessibility for outer suburban residents and spread the transport load around the city.
A considerable amount is known about&amp;nbsp;how these clusters emerge; whether there are underlying patterns to their formation; and how much&amp;nbsp;influence can be applied to these patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A message for the Intergenerational Report: Overseas migration is a bit like the fountain of youth</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/03/06/a_message_for_the_intergenerational_report_overseas_migration_is_enormous_and_keeping_us_young/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 04:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/03/06/a_message_for_the_intergenerational_report_overseas_migration_is_enormous_and_keeping_us_young/</guid>
      <description>It’s pleasing to see the Intergenerational Report focusing on long-term demographic trends and their implications for Australia. It reminds us that international migration has been, and is likely to continue to be, a major factor for change, influencing the pace and the makeup of growth in our communities.
With Advanced Demographic Modelling, we’ve been examining what alternative long-term migration scenarios might mean for different municipalities. Obviously, the scale of net overseas migration has been the key reason some areas have grown rapidly, and it needs to be part of the strategic thinking by councils wishing to address population decline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we really expect CBD densities in regional WA?</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/02/17/can_we_really_expect_cbd_densities_in_regional_wa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 06:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/02/17/can_we_really_expect_cbd_densities_in_regional_wa/</guid>
      <description>The Greater Bunbury area (150km south of Perth) has a population of 75,000 and is forecast to grow to 100,000 by 2031 and 150,000 by 2050. A review of land supply by the State planning authority concluded that demand could be satisfied through a combination of an urban infill program and the release of over 2,000ha of land for Greenfield development. At first glance this seemed plausible. However, a closer examination revealed some fundamental flaws in the underlying assumptions that would have resulted in a land shortage of between 300 and 1,000ha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveability, Efficiency and the Knowledge Economy</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/02/17/liveability_efficiency_and_the_knowledge_economy_92fbc55a_2d2c_4ced_b13d_490df0313618/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 00:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/02/17/liveability_efficiency_and_the_knowledge_economy_92fbc55a_2d2c_4ced_b13d_490df0313618/</guid>
      <description>Liveability, spatial efficiency and the knowledge economy are important to Melbourne’s economic future and the way they are related to one another makes them relevant subject matter for strategic metropolitan planning. This is particularly so for transport infrastructure priorities and whether liveability near knowledge job clusters should be a metropolitan-wide concern. Updating some work done for Melbourne’s 2012 Knowledge Cities conference has revealed some ‘low hanging fruit’ in the spatial distribution of the knowledge sector that may help shed light on the options for a more liveable and efficient city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing market mismatches in Northern Tasmania</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/02/06/housing_market_mismatches_in_northern_tasmania/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2015/02/06/housing_market_mismatches_in_northern_tasmania/</guid>
      <description>In northern Tasmania, the population is growing slowly, but ageing rapidly. While the housing supply pipeline appears to be more than adequate to meet the modest demand, the rapid ageing of the population means that the type of current and planned housing stock is increasingly unsuited to the population, who are living in smaller households, consequently, seeking smaller houses and lots. The counter-intuitive result is that, although, at best, the population may grow by 25% (from around 150,000 to 180,000).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to revitalise an underperforming pedestrian mall</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2014/02/17/how_to_revitalise_an_underperforming_pedestrian_mall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/blog/2014/02/17/how_to_revitalise_an_underperforming_pedestrian_mall/</guid>
      <description>There are many interacting factors that influence the choice an individual makes when deciding where to shop and recreate. Understanding this requires a suitably sophisticated approach based on good evidence. Extensive consultation, including consumer surveys, provided us with data we could use to quantify the relative importance of activation, amenity and retail choice when it comes to where they would shop in the Greater Shepparton area. From this we identified the most cost-effective way to increase visitor numbers to Shepparton’s Maude Street Mall.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>