<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spatial_analysis on Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Analytics</title>
    <link>https://geografia.com.au/categories/spatial_analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spatial_analysis on Geografia: Demography, Economics, Spatial Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2015 - 2017, Geografia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 01:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://geografia.com.au/categories/spatial_analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Jobs in Melbourne&#39;s SE</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/knowledge-jobs-in-melbourne-s-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 01:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/knowledge-jobs-in-melbourne-s-se/</guid>
      <description>Together with regular collaborator, Tim Nott, we investigated how to leverage from existing knowledge-based industries and supply chain components in eastern metropolitan Melbourne. The work formed part of a wider strategy designed to increase jobs in the area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandurah Public Open Space Study</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/mandurah-public-open-space-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 06:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/mandurah-public-open-space-study/</guid>
      <description>Helping the City to take a more evidence-based approach to compiling a strategic plan for the City to affordably development and maintain public open space.&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning for Sustainable Tourism on Tasmania&#39;s East Coast</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/planning-for-sustainable-tourism-on-tasmania-s-east-coast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 03:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/planning-for-sustainable-tourism-on-tasmania-s-east-coast/</guid>
      <description>In partnership with Tim Nott and Hansen, along with cultural heritage and biodiversity specialists, we reviewed options for tourism development along the east coast of Tasmania; examining the challenges faced; opportunities; and investment needs.&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexandra Master Plan</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/alexandra-master-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/alexandra-master-plan/</guid>
      <description>Working with urban designers SJB&amp;nbsp;to activate the old rail precinct in Alexandra through a masterplan. The plan mixes tourism with community use, open space and commercial areas.&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greater Bunbury Global and Regional Futures</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/greater-bunbury-global-and-regional-futures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/greater-bunbury-global-and-regional-futures/</guid>
      <description>An assessment of global, national and regional economic and demographic&amp;nbsp;trends and how they are affecting economic development prospects in Greater Bunbury. The work is part of the State&amp;rsquo;s Regional Centres Development Plan project for eight regional cities. Three key industries are likely to bring in new residents and investment over the next few decades: agribusiness, specialised manufacturing; and tourism.&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Impact of Upgrades to Naracoorte Livestock Exchange</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/value-adding-to-the-naracoorte-livestock-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/value-adding-to-the-naracoorte-livestock-exchange/</guid>
      <description>An economic impact assessment of investing in an upgrade to the livestock exchange shows a net benefit to the region.&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School Site Optimisation in Greater Brisbane</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/school-site-optimisation-in-greater-brisbane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 23:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/school-site-optimisation-in-greater-brisbane/</guid>
      <description>Following on from the work in Moreton Bay, we further developed the school demand forecasting technique to determine whether a proposed new school site would minimise school catchment area overlaps in a region with a rapidly growing population.&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School Demand Forecasting in Moreton Bay</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/school-demand-forecasting-in-moreton-bay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 02:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/school-demand-forecasting-in-moreton-bay/</guid>
      <description>A statistical and GIS-based analysis of school demand to identify the optimum site for a new school in Moreton Bay on behalf of Brisbane Catholic Education (BCE). It uses&amp;nbsp;real enrolment data, analysing trends over time to develop a probabilistic model of the growth rates for new catchment areas. This factors in travel patterns and &amp;lsquo;attractiveness&amp;rsquo; features to identify the better of two locations for a new school in the rapidly growing region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murchison Plan</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/murchison-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 23:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/murchison-plan/</guid>
      <description>A resource analysis and community statement leading to a regional development framework for the five councils that make up north and western Tasmania. The work included an extensive land suitability assessment and collaboration with environmental and transport&amp;nbsp;planners and community engagement specialists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Court Service Demand Modelling</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/court-demand-modelling-across-victoria/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 00:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/court-demand-modelling-across-victoria/</guid>
      <description>A multi-jurisdictional service demand model to estimate future court activity across 50 regions around Victoria. It uses probabilistic (Monte Carlo) modelling to factor in uncertainty around demand, demographic, technology and policy changes and informs GHD&amp;rsquo;s service plan for Court Services Victoria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospect Vale Structure Plan</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/prospect-vale-structure-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 03:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/prospect-vale-structure-plan/</guid>
      <description>In partnership with David Locke Associates and Arup, we have prepared a structure plan to guide development in this fast growing part of northern Tasmania.
Image: Prospect Vale activity centre; concept drawing (Geografia &amp;amp; DLA, 2014)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victorian Small Towns Study</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/victorian-small-towns-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 03:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/victorian-small-towns-study/</guid>
      <description>Working with Melbourne firm Planisphere, the study examined 31 Victorian towns, all with fewer than a thousand residents, and explored their changing nature and the contributions they make in regional Victoria. As part of the case studies, we undertook economic and demographic modelling, geographic information system (GIS) and consultation. The project outcomes supported the State Government’s regional growth plans.
Image: Corryong outskirts (Geografia, 2012)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Need for High Speed Broadband</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/the-need-for-high-speed-broadband/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 01:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/the-need-for-high-speed-broadband/</guid>
      <description>A study to measure the economic benefits of redirecting the NBN rollout in Melbourne’s South East to prioritise three key industrial precincts. It involved a survey of business operators, along with an economic and GIS analysis to develop a statement of quantitative benefit of the merits of changing the rollout plan.
Image: iStock</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wanneroo Land Use Vision</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/wanneroo-land-use-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 23:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/wanneroo-land-use-vision/</guid>
      <description>A 50 year strategic vision to guide the City onto a more sustainable pathway. After detailed demographic and economic analysis we worked with the City and residents to prepare a strategic plan for land development, transport and community infrastruture planning that would help the City move closer towards the City envisaged its residents and businesses. After its conclusion, we went on to undertake a public open space study and several smaller projects investigating the options for the redevelopment of specific Council facilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karratha 2020</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/karratha-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 23:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/karratha-2020/</guid>
      <description>A detailed study of community and economic development needs in Karratha. Consulting with business and residents and mapping out a detailed plan for community infrastructure priorities. Following on from this we prepared an economic prospectus for Roebourne and undertook a cost benefit analysis of infrastructure plans. We also ran several land use and community satisfaction surveys on behalf of the Shire.
Image: K2020 Vision (cover page)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brimbank National Employment Cluster Study</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/brimbank-national-emploment-cluster-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 22:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/brimbank-national-emploment-cluster-study/</guid>
      <description>A study mapping and analysing the potential scale and nature of employment growth in the Brimbank National Employment Cluster. It involved extensive economic modelling and GIS analysis to determine three likely growth scenarios for the Cluster and the net employment gain that the Cluster could accommodate as it expands.&amp;nbsp;
We incorporated uncertainty into the modelling by composing probability ranges for key decisions (e.g. to invest in new transport infrastructure) and processes (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgetown World Heritage Precinct Land Use Survey</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/georgetown-world-heritage-precinct-baseline-land-use-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 00:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/georgetown-world-heritage-precinct-baseline-land-use-survey/</guid>
      <description>We built on our 2010 census of the World Heritage Area in George Town, Penang&amp;nbsp;with the development, rollout and analysis of a detailed assessment of households and businesses in the port precinct.&amp;nbsp;
Photo:&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;Old town of Georgetown.&amp;rdquo; by Milei.vencel - Own work. Licensed under CC BY-SA 3.0 via Wikimedia Commons - http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Old_town_of_Georgetown..JPG#mediaviewer/File:Old_town_of_Geor...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greater Bunbury Population and Housing Capacity Review</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/greater-bunbury-population-and-housing-capacity-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 23:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/greater-bunbury-population-and-housing-capacity-review/</guid>
      <description>As part of a review of the population growth assumptions underpinning the Greater Bunbury Strategy, we deployed our housing and population capacity model to estimate the land required to accommodate expected population growth in the Greater Bunbury Region. We found that the increase in density was likely&amp;nbsp;be slower than expected and that this would result in a&amp;nbsp;shortfall of up to 700ha of residential land by build out.&amp;nbsp;
As with all forecasting we do, we used a probabilistic model to account for the uncertainty in the population growth and other key factors such as household size, dwelling choice,&amp;nbsp;vacancy rates and rate of construction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Opportunities from High Water Security in Wodonga</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/high-water-security-in-wodonga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/high-water-security-in-wodonga/</guid>
      <description>An analysis of the City&amp;rsquo;s comparative advantages in water-intensive manufacturing. The project highlighted good prospects for food and beverage manufacturing, which benefits from a number of other local advantages including low water and other input costs; access to a skilled workforce; and a good logistics network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgetown Conurbation Spatial Strategy</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/georgetown-conurbation-spatial-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/georgetown-conurbation-spatial-strategy/</guid>
      <description>The Malaysian Federal Government, through Think City commissioned Geografia to research and prepare a spatial strategy for Northern Malaysia. Encompassing land use planning, economic and demographic analysis, we prepared a 20 point plan for making strategic land use planning decisions that would assist with national development goals. The first plan was prepared in 2009 and we updated it in 2014. Amongst other things, we examined and modelled economic development opportunities in manufacturing, agribusiness, tourism, hi tech R&amp;amp;D and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broome Economic Development Strategy</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/broome-economic-development-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/broome-economic-development-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Landcorp, the Shire of Broome and the Kimberley Development Commission worked with Geografia to profile and investigate the Shire&amp;rsquo;s economic state of play&amp;nbsp;and its prospects for growth in light of global and regional conditions.&amp;nbsp;To ensure Broome becomes&amp;nbsp;the region&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;supertown&amp;rsquo; required strategic decision-making informed by&amp;nbsp;consultation, data analysis, population and economic forecasting. This charted a trajectory for Broome that would balance mining services, tourism and agribusiness.&amp;nbsp;
Image: Broome economic regions (Geografia, 2014)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newcastle Urban Renewal Study</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/newcastle-urban-renewal-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 07:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/newcastle-urban-renewal-study/</guid>
      <description>A regional economic development research exercise commissioned by UrbanGrowth NSW. This project identified growth opportunities for central Newcastle. The aim was to find ways in which the City could use its competitive advantages, particularly in agribusiness, tourism and existing assets, to diversify its economy and bring more jobs and residents back to the down town&amp;nbsp;area.&amp;nbsp;
Image: Newcastle central area (Geografia, 2014)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moreland Industrial Land Strategy</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/moreland-industrial-land-use-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 02:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/moreland-industrial-land-use-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Working with Tim Nott, using site surveys, GIS and economic modelling, we have estimated the current economic value of industrial sites throughout Moreland. The work is being used to inform rezoning decisions in light of residential development pressures, particularly in the southern part of the municipality.
Image: Mapping industrial precincts and activity centres in Moreland City (Geografia, 2014)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling School Demand</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/estimating-school-enrolment-demands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 23:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/estimating-school-enrolment-demands/</guid>
      <description>The school demand model we developed&amp;nbsp;represents a step change in the way future demand for schools can be predicted. At its heart is a powerful statistical technique called kernel density estimation linked to a GIS-based ‘school supply model’. This decision-support tool delivers a reliable estimate of government, catholic and independent primary and secondary school demand. It considers location, ethnicity, income, household size and other demographic characteristics of the catchment area. Broader effects such as underlying school preference and government education policy shifts are also included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golden Plains Economic Development &amp; Tourism Strategy</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/golden-plains-economic-development-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/golden-plains-economic-development-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Produced ahead of schedule, and in partnership with regular consulting economist Tim Nott, the background report and draft strategy involved extensive modelling, consultation exercises and an online survey. Our work has given us an up-to-date and thorough understanding of economic, major project and development issues in the G21 region.
Image: Golden Plains economic landscape (Geografia, 2013)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greater Launceston Plan</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/greater-launceston-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 23:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/greater-launceston-plan/</guid>
      <description>We completed three of the seven components of the Liveable Cities&amp;rsquo; Greater Launceston Plan (a 20 year part Commonwealth-funded land use plan). First off was the community statement; a thorough documentation of community profiles across the six municipalities that made up the region.
Part two - the resource analysis - included population, housing and employment modelling designed to map out different growth scenarios and land use suitability. This included the range of probable growth, employment and housing trends into the modelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment and Skills Gaps in Outer Metropolitan Growth Areas</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/employment-and-skills-gaps-in-outer-metropolitan-growth-areas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 07:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/employment-and-skills-gaps-in-outer-metropolitan-growth-areas/</guid>
      <description>Working with Melbourne firm, Essential Economics, we undertook a study into the economic conditions and prospects for the 25 councils that make up the National Growth Areas Alliance. Geografia developed a jobs and skills deficit measure that plotted each council according to whether their priority concerns were a lack of jobs, skills or both. The current trajectory for each council was also plotted. A strategy for intervention was prepared. Its foundation was the creation of skills ecosystems that would target 20,000 more jobs in two years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lindenow Agricultural Intensification Cost Benefit Analysis</title>
      <link>https://geografia.com.au/projects/lindenow-agricultural-intensification-cost-benefit-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geografia.com.au/projects/lindenow-agricultural-intensification-cost-benefit-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Our land use optimisation model was used to predict land use change in response to greater water security in the Lindenow Valley in East Gippsland. This model identifies the thresholds at which land can be turned over to commercial crops. Improved water security then becomes the catalyst for investment, an increase in employment and, subsequently, local population. The module factors in rainfall, water availability and other production costs and outputs are farm gate sales, regional multipliers, the impact on population growth and likely demand for essential services.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>